<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pejuang rupiah</title>
    <description>pejuang rupiah berita blogger tentang kumpulan berbagai informasi terbaru dan berita onlien berbagai sumber.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 18:43:21 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 18:43:21 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips For Stopping Spraying</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Anytime your cat backs himself up to a door or other object in your house, lifts his tail, and releases urine , you have a problem.  This problem is known as spraying, and is very common with cats kept indoors.  Even though it is a very annoying problem, it’s a problem that can be solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what many think, spraying isn’t a litter box problem, but rather a problem with marking.  Cat urine that is sprayed contains pheromones, which is a substance that cats and other animals use for communicating.  Pheromones are much like fingerprints with humans, as they are used to identify the cat to other animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a cat sprays something, he is simply marking his territory through his urine.  The spraying is simply the cat’s way of letting others know that the territory is his.  Even though it may make you mad and annoy you, getting angry with your cat will solve nothing.  If you raise your voice or show angry towards your cat, it can very well result in more spraying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats that are in heat are easily attracted to the odor of urine.  For cats in heat, spraying is more or less an invitation for love.  Often times cats that spray while in heat results in a litter of kittens that are born in just a few short months.  Keep in mind that cats not only spray during heat, as some will also spray during encounters with other cats, or when they are feeling stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although spraying is a way of communicating for cats, the smell for people is horrible.  The good thing here is that most cats will do a majority of their spraying outdoors.  If you have an indoor cat that never goes outside, spraying can indeed be a problem.  If you’ve noticed spraying in your home, you should take action and do something about it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective and also the easiest way to stop spraying is to have your cat either neutered or spayed, which of course depends on the sex.  Most male cats that have been neutered will stop spraying the same day they have the surgery. If you don’t want to get your cat neutered or spayed, you should look into other options.  If you hope to one day breed your cat, you certainly don’t want to have him neutered or spayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing to do in this situation is to talk to your veterinarian.  He will be able to give you advice, and possibly even solve the problem without having surgery.  There may be a medical problem present that is causing the problem, which your vet can identify.  You should always do something about spraying the moment it starts , simply because cat urine stinks and it can leave stains all over your home.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:12:35 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/tips-for-stopping-spraying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tips-for-stopping-spraying/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips For Introducing Cats</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;When you decide to add a new cat to your home, it’s normally more exiting for you and your family than it is for the cat you already own.  Although most cats are solitary by nature, most will also come to accept or eventually tolerate any additions.  Cats can be very territorial, which is why you should always be careful when you introduce a new cat to your current cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are introducing kittens to one another, the entire introduction process can be short, lasting as little as 10 , 15 days.  Introducing cats to each other all depends on their temperament and their personality.  When you introduce a new cat to your current cat, you should always make sure that you give your current cat plenty of love and attention.  This way, your cat will feel secure and know that he isn’t in competition with your new cat for affection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you bring your new cat home, you should let him stay in a safe room until you have finished introducing the cats.  Your safe room can be any small room in your home, such as a bathroom or spare bedroom.   The key here is to use a room that your current cat doesn’t go in.  In the room, you should leave your new cat a scratching post, bed, water dish, litter box, and food dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, your current cat may howl and hiss when he stands at the door, trying to tell the other cat that he doesn’t belong.  When this happens you should ignore it, as punishing your cat for his behavior will only lead to more problems.  After a while, the first cat will start to act calm when he is near the new cat’s door.  As he starts to act calm, you should pet him and give him praise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your first cat starts to go by your new cat’s door and doesn’t howl or hiss; you can start introducing them to each other.  The best way to do this is to get them used to each others scent.  You can start letting them eat out of the same food dish, although you’ll want to feed them at different intervals at first.  This way, the scent of each cat will be present at the food dish, and each cat will get the scent when he eats his food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once both cats have got used to the scent, you can begin to feed them closer together.  To do this, you should keep your new cat in the safe room with the door closed, and your first cat on the other side of the door with his food dish.  This time, feed both cats at the same time.  After doing this a few times, they should start eating without any hissing or growling.  At this point, they are ready to be introduced to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you introduce them to each other in the same room, a bit of growling and hissing is to be expected.  Although they may be used to each others scent; your first cat will still feel a bit awkward with your new cat being in his territory.  You should play with them both at first, so they can smell one another and greet in their own way. If they start to fight you should break them up, and give them some time apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may take some time to get them fully used to one another, although once they do , they will become playmates for life.  Cats love to be social, although it may be a bit rough at first, especially for your first cat.  Cats can be very territorial, especially if you have a kitten around.  If you get both of them used to each other early on , it will be a lot easier to add future cats to your home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:12:27 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/tips-for-introducing-cats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tips-for-introducing-cats/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things To Know Before Breeding Your Cat</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;The population of cats is the United States alone is unbelievable.  Nearly all experts will tell you that you should spay your cat instead of breed it.  No matter what experts have to say, a lot of people want to have a litter of kittens from their cat.  Before you decide to breed your cat, there are a few things that you should think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you should know is that breeding cats takes time.  For the next two months after the litter is born, you’ll need to clean the area on a daily basis.  You’ll also need to watch over the kittens as well, and keep a close eye on how they are developing.  If you plan to breed a litter of cats, you won’t have time for much of anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breeding cats will also require a good degree of space as well.  If you have a small apartment, you shouldn’t attempt to breed a cat.  You should also make sure that your family agrees with the idea, as it isn’t good for the kittens if you keep them locked up.  Keep in mind that kittens like to see things; they’ll end up going all over your home as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breeding cats also requires a degree of responsibility as well.  You should always have a plan of approach, including homes for the kittens to go that you aren’t planning to keep.  Keep in mind that things can change, someone who wanted a cat may change his mind once the litter is born.  In this event, you must decide whether or not you can keep a kitten that doesn’t have a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breeding also requires some education as well.  You should be prepared for any problems along the way, as well as what takes place during birth.  From cutting umbilical cords to delivering early, you’ll need to be well prepared.  You should also have the proper supplies, and know how to handle things in the event of a c-section.  You’ll also need to know what to feed pregnant cats, as their diets are very important if you are breeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breeding will also cost money as well, with kittens costing a lot more money than you may think.  The food isn’t the only thing that’s expensive, as the vet bills can also get expensive.  Even though you may go through the entire pregnancy without going to the vet, you’ll still need de-worming and vaccination medicines as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, there is a lot to think about where breeding is concerned. If you have your mind set on it and you want to breed, you should be sure that you have the proper knowledge and everything you need before hand.  You should always be ready to handle anything associated with breeding , and prepare yourself for the worst possible scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:12:19 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/things-to-know-before-breeding-your-cat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/things-to-know-before-breeding-your-cat/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things To Know About Abused Cats</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Cats that have been abused can appear severely maimed and damaged all over their exterior.  Some may appear to be in perfect shape on the outside, although all of the damage they sustained may be internal or emotional.  Even though physical damage is bad, emotional damage is much tougher to fix.  Cats who have physical abuse will still answer to a soft touch and soft voice, as long as they know that the abuse has come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a cat that has been emotionally abused, you’ll need to wait until the cat comes to you.  You’ll need to use patience, as the cat will be confused and not know if you plan to hurt him or not.  If you take your time and let him know that you are nothing to fear, he will eventually come to you.  When he starts to come to you, you can let him sniff you and pet him.  After a while, he will learn that he can trust you and he will come to you when you call him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yelling, raising your voice, or using disciplinary tools such as flyswatters or water guns the wrong way can lead to emotional damage.  If you continue to use the wrong means of discipline on an emotionally damaged cat, the cat can become mean or lethargic.  When a cat turns mean, it’s not always a bad thing.  Meaner cats are easier to reach, as they still care a bit about what happens to them and while lethargic cats could really care less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats that have become lethargic won’t play, take treats, or respond to anything you say to them.  With a lethargic cat, the ideal way to get him to respond is to bring in a companion cat.  Over time, a lethargic cat will eventually look for attention, normally a scratch or a pat.  When this happens, you should always use a soft voice and snuggle with him.  Never raise your voice at this point, and make sure you let the cat know that his behavior is a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should make slow movements around a lethargic cat, as he is still quite traumatic.  Once he is coming around and letting you touch him again, he is getting back to his normal self.  Keep in mind that it may take some time, which is to be expected with this type of situation.  If your cat starts to get upset again or if you raise your voice, he will hide again.  If you continue to use a soft voice and have patience, your cat will eventually get past this.  If you get a cat that is lethargic, you should prepare yourself for a long and very intensive healing period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angry or mean cats on the other hand, will either fight and scratch with you, or simply run away from you.  With mean cats, the best thing to do is use gentle treatment with a soft voice.  You can never try to raise your voice or use strict discipline, as it will only make the cat meaner.  Never attempt to trap the cat either, as trapping it will only make the cat react.  If you take your time and let the cat know that you are there for him, he will eventually calm down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abused cats are truly a sad thing, although they are out there.  Abused cats can be a sad thing to see indeed, especially those that were physically abused.  Abused cats need a loving home and a loving owner who will give them the type of lifestyle they deserve.  Always remember that if you are dealing with an abused cat and you should always be as gentle as you possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:12:11 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/things-to-know-about-abused-cats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/things-to-know-about-abused-cats/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cruelty Of Claw Removal</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Cats use their claws for various purposes.  The claws are important to cats, as they are an essential part of balancing.  If you’ve ever noticed a cat jumping and latching on to a high object, you’ve probably noticed that he uses his claws to pull himself up.  When climbing trees, cats tend to use their claws to latch onto the bark and climb towards their destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats also use their claws for stretching, walking, and running as well.  The claws are also a cat’s primary source of defense against other animals and humans as well.  Most cats keep their claws extremely sharp, as their claws and teeth are basically their only weapons.  The claws are also essential for using the bathroom as well, as cats use them to cover up their mess with dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats also use their claws to scratch things, which mark their territory.  Their claws have glands, which contain a secretion.  When they leave their mark on something, the secretion is transferred to the area they scratched.  This is detectable to other cats although not to humans.  Sometimes, they will also scratch something to remove the older claw which will fall off and give them a brand new claw that resides underneath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As sad as it is, a lot of pet owners choose to put their own possessions above their cat, such as their expensive furniture or carpets.  These cat owners are afraid that they cat will ruin their furniture or carpet, and therefore will choose to get their cat de-clawed.  Getting a cat’s claws removed is a surgical procedure, one that can only be performed by a veterinarian.  The owner will need a good reason though, as a vet won’t do the surgery just to keep one’s furniture or carpet protected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been thinking of getting your cat de-clawed, you should know that the process can totally change his personality.  Once the cat is de-clawed, he will be in pain and confused.  He may not be able to jump in the window or on the couch, and he may not be able to play like he once did.  Some cats, after being de-clawed, tend to get aggressive and bite with their teeth.  To make a long story short, the cat will be completely miserable and which is a tough thing to bear for those who love their cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who decide to own cats should know that a cat can scratch on occasion.  If someone isn’t prepared to deal with that fact, they shouldn’t own a cat in the first place.  Cats are great pets, although they do have claws and they will use them on occasion.  There are plenty of other great pets out there, if you aren’t up for handling a cat.  If you’re just worried about your furniture or carpet, there are ways that you can keep your cat from scratching on your belongings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is to get your cat a scratching post and let him know where it is and how to use it.  You can also get a rush mat as well, which will help your cat with his instincts to scratch.  You may have to demonstrate how to use the mat or the post at first, although your cat should catch onto it quick.  Once you have shown him the ropes, he will scratch on the post or the mat , and not your furniture or your carpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although many don’t realize it, there are other ways to protect your things other than getting your cat de-clawed.  Getting a cat’s claws removed is very painful and confusing to the cat, and may totally change his outlook on things.  Before you decide to take the inhumane path of getting your cat de-clawed, you should look into your other available options- your cat will like these options much better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:12:02 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/the-cruelty-of-claw-removal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-cruelty-of-claw-removal/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cat Whisperer</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;A cat whisper is somewhat similar to a dog or horse whisperer, although cat whisperers relate quite well with cats.  These types of people are unusually lucky and very successfully with cats.  In most cases, a cat will be abandoned or just show up at someone’s door.  In this event, the cat will adopt this individual as the cat whisperer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times, alley cats and black cats will show up at someone’s door and decide to move into their homes.  This can be a result of abandonment, or the cat’s family moving away and simply leaving the cat behind.  Sometimes, the cat may decide that he likes someone else’s home better and decide to move there instead of staying with his owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people will tell you that a cat whisperer can be thought of as a therapist for cats.  Almost all cat whisperers haven’t have any type of training, what they know just seems to come to them naturally.  These types of people understand the way a cat thinks and knows how to work with the cat to achieve the results they want.  Even though many think of a cat whisperer as a therapist, it actually couldn’t be further from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats who have been abused or mistreated, often times won’t respond to anyone but a cat whisperer.  Although others may have tried to help the cat, it will only make matters worse by making the cat feel scared and afraid.  In most cases, these cats will end up in a pound.  This is very tragic, as the cats have already endured more than they ever should have.  A majority of the cats who have been abused were once loved pets.  Along the way, they were abandoned, mistreated, attacked by dogs, and in some cases tortured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats who have been treated unfairly often times won’t trust anyone. They are often times confused, in a lot of pain, and not sure what they should do.  Like humans, cats feel pain.  Those that have been physically abused are a sad sight indeed.  Emotionally damaged cats may appear to be in perfect health on the outside, although their emotions are a wreck.  Emotionally abused cats are much harder to get through to, especially if they were stray cats to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cat whisperers on the other hand, can communicate with physically and emotionally abused cats.  Cats know who they will choose to be their cat whisperer, which is normally an individual they sense trust with.  Cat whisperers are common with cats, although most people have never heard of them before.  Even though a cat whisperer may be able to communicate better with cats, it will still take time to heal a cat that has been abused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:11:52 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/the-cat-whisperer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-cat-whisperer/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Amazing Cat Species</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;We all know that cats are loving and truly wonderful creatures.  These days, it isn’t out of the ordinary to see a cat in virtually every other home, sleeping in the window or cuddling up on the laps of their owners.  Although cats have been popular pets for as long as most can remember, they weren’t domesticated less than 5,000 years or so ago.  Domestication took place in the valley of the Nile, which is what research tells us today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, people were very grateful to cats and encouraged them to stay with them by feeding them various scraps of food.  Once they were fed and perceived humans to be no threat, the cats would move in permanently with their human owners.  As time went by, even the wildest of cat would allows humans to approach him, often times even hold and touch as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those days, cats were very loyal and endearing pets.  They proved to be great hunters, as they done their sleeping in short periods and were much easier to wake up than dogs.  Cats also have better night vision than dogs, and much better hearing as well.  If someone moved through the house or if they heard suspicious noises, they would wake while dogs would sleep right through it.  Humans loved having cats around, and they seemed to get along good with dogs as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, cats are used for both companionship and show.  They aren’t used much at all for hunting mice and rodent anymore at all.  There are a lot of breeds available, from the traditional alley cat to the well known Siamese.  All breeds are unique in their own way, and will provide you with years of companionship if you take care of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you get a kitten or older cat, you’ll first want to examine the source.  If you are getting the kitten from a breeder, you’ll want to make sure that the breeder has a reputable reputation.  You’ll also want to ensure that the cattery is clean and in good shape.  The kittens that are still there shouldn’t be overcrowded, and their surroundings should be clean.  The litter boxes there should be kept up and both the food and water dish should be clean and full.  The kittens shouldn’t be caged, instead free to run around.  All cats that are there should appear healthy, with shiny coats and none of their ribs showing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get your kitten, it should be used to being touched and handled.  The kitten should be sweet, not afraid in the least.  Kittens that have been handled young normally have a better temperament.  The better breeders won’t allow their kittens to leave the nest until they are around 12 weeks old, with some waiting until the kittens are 16 weeks.  By doing this, breeders ensure that the kitten is in good health and his immune system has properly developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no mistaken the fact that cats are great to own.  You can get a kitten from a reputable breeder, through a local newspaper, or an adoption agency.  Cats can also be obtained from a local pound, although people normally don’t like to choose this option.  No matter which way you decide to pursue, you should always make sure that your cat is healthy.  If you get a healthy cat, you won’t have a lot of problems later on down the road.  Healthy cats were taken care of , and normally have everything up to date , including their vaccinations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:11:43 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/the-amazing-cat-species/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-amazing-cat-species/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Taking Care Of Cats</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;These days, cats are among the most popular pet you can own.  There are several breeds available, with the most popular being Persian and Siamese.  Cats are a domesticated animal, with origins dating back some 8,000 years and beyond.  Like any other pet that you may own, including dogs, cats cost money to take care of properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get a cat, you’ll need to think about the costs.  You’ll obviously need food, and you’ll also need to plan ahead for vet costs.  You’ll also need litter, which can tend to get quite expensive as the years go by.  Your cat will need a litter box, food dish, and water dish.  You should also invest in some toys as well, such as a scratching post, cat toys, a pet carrier, and a bed.  You should also look into getting an ID collar as well, just in case your cat ever gets lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeding your pet will depend a great deal on his age.  Older cats require two small meals or one large meal for the day.  Kittens on the other hand, require several feedings a day until they get around the age of 12 weeks.  Cats that are between three and six months of age need to be fed three times a day.  Canned food can be fed to cats, although any food that has been left out longer than 30 minutes need to be disposed of.  Canned food can get expensive fast, and you should always keep in mind that some may need to be thrown away when you buy it.  Cats loved canned food, although it doesn’t have any benefits to their dental health like dry food does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an alternative plan, you can always leave a supply of dry food out for your pet.  When you give your cat dry food, you should always make sure that he has enough water.  Dry food costs less than canned food, and it can also help to prevent the buildup of tartar on your cat’s teeth.  When you buy dry food, you should always look in terms of health and benefits, and stay away from generic food.  Even though generic food may be cheaper, it may not offer the nutrients your pet needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a kitten, you should only give you kitten food designed for him.  You’ll also need to clean and refill his water dish every day.  Even though kittens and adult cats like cow’s milk, you should avoid giving it to them as it can cause diarrhea.  Treats are fine on occasion, although too many of them can cause your pet to get fat.  Feeding your kitten human food is good on occasion, although you may have to mix it in with his cat food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By themselves, cats stay fairly clean.  Although you don’t have to bathe them that often, you’ll need to give them a brushing at least once a day.  Brushing will reduce the risk of hairballs and keep your cat’s coat nice and clean.  If you are keeping your cat indoors, you’ll need to have a litter box in an area that is easy for your cat to access.  You should always scoop it on a daily basis, and clean it out once a week.  Cats don’t like to use dirty litter boxes, they prefer for it to be nice and clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although cats do require some work, they are great pets that will provide you with years and years of companionship.  As long as you take care of your cat and take him to the vet for his checkups, he should remain healthy.  Even though cats can get sick from time to time and knowing how to care for him will make a world of difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:11:36 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/taking-care-of-cats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/taking-care-of-cats/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Litter Cleaning For Cats</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone, adults and kids alike have a natural fondness for cats.  They are loving, quiet, and very playful pets that can provide you with years of entertainment.  Although most of us have a fondness for cats, that fondness can rapidly diminish when it comes to the litter box.  Even the most hardened cat lover may get tired of litter box duty, especially when it comes down to scooping you know what from the litter box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cats are very intelligent, instinctively knowing how they should use the litter box.  After the cat has finished using the litter box, someone in the family will need to scoop the waste from the litter box.  This can be a very dirty and somewhat smelly job, one that is often overlooked during the day when the workload gets heavy. Cleaning up the litter box doesn’t take but a few minutes, although most would prefer not to do it at all.  Although the litter box will need to be scooped out daily, it will also need to be changed once a week as well, by throwing the current bag out and replacing the box with a new bag and fresh litter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who don’t like to scoop out the litter box should invest in one of the best inventions ever , the self cleaning litter box.  These litter boxes are easy to use, and will keep the area clean.  After the cat has used it, the self cleaning litter box will automatically clean the litter either by sifting or using a device that resembles a rake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self cleaning boxes that use shifting will often times have a round design.  Once the cat leaves the covered box, the dome on top will revolve for the box to clean.  The litter in the box will be shifted with the waste being put below the litter where it is discarded.  Once the waste is properly disposed of, the litter will be returned to its normal position in the box for the cat to use again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boxes that have raking systems will often times sport a rectangular design.  Once the cat leaves the box, the rake will automatically come out and clean the litter.  The rake will clean all of the litter in the box, including the clumps of waste as well.  Rakes are popular, although the shifting litter boxes are by far more popular and more common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who are often times away from home could greatly benefit from a self cleaning litter box.  They are great to have for cats that spend a lot of time by themselves, as they virtually eliminate any scooping of litter on your part.  You can find them at your local pet or department store, even online as well.  They are very affordable , and ideal for anyone who doesn’t like scooping waste from their litter box.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:11:26 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/litter-cleaning-for-cats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/litter-cleaning-for-cats/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Helping Your Cat Stay Healthy</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;To keep your cat healthy a majority of time, all you really need to do is give him good shelter, food, and plenty of water.  Like other living things however, cats can get sick from time to time no matter what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a cat owner, you’ll want to ensure that you feed your cat only the best.  Premium cat food is the ideal for cats, as the food is designed to keep your pet happy and healthy.  You’ll also need to pay attention to his behavior, so you’ll know when he’s sick and when to take him to the vet.  Most of the more common ailments and sicknesses are minor, although there are some cases where a vet can be the determining factor between life and death for your cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your cat’s behavior will be one of the most critical factors when you are trying to determine whether or not he is under the weather.  Acting sluggish, laying around all the time, lack of energy and not eating are all signs that you need to take him to the vet immediately.  His coat is also a good thing to watch as well.  If you notice his coat dull and patchy or notice him shedding abnormally, you should contact your vet as soon as you possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diarrhea and vomiting are sometimes common, even with basic sickness.  On the other hand, if your cat seems to be doing either one of the two for more than a day, you should contact your veterinarian.  Coughing is common as well, simply because coughing will cats dislodge hairballs.  If your cat seems to be coughing for another reason, you should have him checked out as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure that your cat isn’t subjected to various diseases, you should always make sure that he stays up do date with his vaccinations. There are several diseases out there that require vaccinations, including rabies and feline distemper.  Feline distemper is one of most devastating diseases a cat can get, yet it is also one of the easiest to prevent as well.  The disease strikes cats very fast, and leaves you as an own very little time to seek treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feline leukemia is another disease that is very deadly, yet can be prevented early on with the proper vaccinations.  Although the disease isn’t possible for humans to contract, it can be spread quickly among cats.  There are vaccinations that can treat the disease these days, although you’ll still want to be careful and not expose other cats around a cat you know has feline leukemia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem, which is very common with cats that stay outdoors, is worms.  Cats that have worms will normally have a lackluster coat and little to no appetite.   There are several different types of worms, including ringworm and hookworm.  Worms can come from fleas, lice, or even the organs of dead rodents that cats consume.  Normally, the cat will digest the eggs which will later mature and attach themselves to the walls of the intestines.  If you feed your cat garlic frequently during feedings, it can help to protect him against worms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take care of your cat, chances are you’ll keep him healthy for years to come.  You should always make sure he has quality food, and doesn’t miss any of his scheduled checkups with the vet.  If he gets the proper vaccinations when he is required to get them, he should be safe against numerous pests and diseases.  Taking the proper steps with your cat now will prevent anything from happening in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:11:17 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>/helping-your-cat-stay-healthy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/helping-your-cat-stay-healthy/</guid>
        
        <category>cats</category>
        
        
        <category>Cats</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
